jobsjobsjobs.com.au 2016-12-13

# Privacy | jobsjobsjobs.com.au | Australia's biggest jobs network

In today’s times we all need to be smart in the way we handle our personal information, who we give it out to and what they will do with it.  At jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd we understand how important the information is that you tell us when you use the jobsjobsjobs Site. We take it very seriously. 

We believe we are at the forefront of the privacy issues in our industry and as a result we continue to improve and refine the way we protect your personal information.  We feel it is important that you understand how protective we are and how we manage your valuable information, so we have developed a ‘Privacy Charter’ that all our staff are committed too, passionately. 

This Privacy Charter details the commitment of jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd to protect your information when you use the jobsjobsjobs Site at www.jobsjobsjobs.com.au(Site).  We ask that you to read this charter and familiarise yourself about how we approach this important issue before you use the Site. 

jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd adheres to and complies with the National Privacy Principles and the Privacy Act 1998 (Cth). 

This Privacy Charter sets out jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd’s policies for managing personal information across jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd and all of its businesses, operating within Australia. 

A Privacy Officer, who is responsible for all matters pertaining to privacy, has been appointed at jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd and this person’s contact details are provided in this Privacy Charter under the heading ‘Privacy Officer’, below. 

### Your Acceptance 

This Privacy Charter applies to and should be read in conjunction with the Terms and Conditions which are available on the Site.  You can also request a copy from jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd by writing to the privacy officer. 

By viewing and using the Site, you will be deemed to have agreed to the matters described in this Privacy Charter. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Charter, then you should stop accessing and using the Site immediately. 

Further, you should review this Privacy Charter regularly, as it may be updated from time to time, at jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd’s discretion. 

### Privacy Statement

jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd utilises the latest technological advances to target consumers’ lifestyles and supply the highest level of service without compromising usability and content of the Site and its features. 

In each of its businesses, jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd has relationships with customers to whom it provides various services.   As part of these customer relationships, jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd collects information necessary to enrol customers in products and services and to offer them additional or related products and services. 

As mentioned previously, jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd takes the protection of personal information very seriously and zealously protects the privacy of individuals, including customers, clients and service providers. This Privacy Charter will serve the interests of all persons in respect of whom jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd collects personal information and will provide jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd with an effective method to provide privacy protection. 

### Types of Personal Information We Collect

Generally, we collect personal information that is needed to facilitate and to provide the services and products offered to you via our Site. 

The types of personal information that we collect from you will depend on – 

(a) the circumstances of collection; and 

(b) the type of service you request from us.

For example, when you register with us, we may collect details such as your name, address, telephone numbers and other relevant information. We generally do not collect “sensitive information” (as this term is defined in the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth), which includes information relating to ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs, membership of a political or trade association, sexual preferences or health) and would not do so without your consent. 

However, there may be instances where such information becomes necessary or is part of a curriculum vitae.  In such an event, the law requires us to obtain your consent to the collection of “sensitive information”. If you provide us with this information, we will assume that you have consented to the collection of that information for use in accordance with this Privacy Charter unless you expressly inform us otherwise.  Please note that if you choose not to privide us with this information, this may impact on our ability to provide our products and services to you. 

### When we collect your personal information

We collect personal information at the time you make an enquiry or purchase with us.  We only require information necessary to complete the transaction or for you to undertake a relevant search or job application. 

### **Why We Collect Personal Information**

Generally, we collect, update and use personal information about you to carry on our business, including – 

  * to carry out transactions you wish to make;
  * to provide or facilitate the provision of requested products and services;
  * to collect payment for the products and services you purchase;
  * for our research and development purposes;
  * for training, quality control and verification purposes;
  * to communicate our, a related company’s, or a third party’s marketing offers to you; and
  * to meet our legal obligations.

### **How We Collect Personal Information**

Generally, we will collect personal information directly from you, either in person, by telephone, letter, facsimile, email, or when you visit our Site. We may also request information from you when you purchase or make enquiries about our products or services, when you register for promotions or when you request brochures or other information. We may also collect information when we invite you to complete surveys or provide us with feedback. 

There may be circumstances where we collect information about you from third parties. For example, we may obtain information from market research companies, contracted by us to obtain information so that we may improve and market our products and services. 

### **How We Store information**

We store personal information in a combination of secure computer storage facilities and paper based files and other records. We have implemented systems and processes to protect the personal information we hold from misuse, loss and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We use generally accepted technology and security measures so your information will be transmitted safely to us through the internet or other electronic means.  When we no longer require your personal information, we will take reasonable steps to securely destroy or permanently de–identify it. 

### **How We Use Your Personal Information**

Once you have provided us with your personal information, we use it for the purposes for which it was collected. Generally, this will involve the use of your personal information by us to deliver products and services that you have requested and to process transactions you conduct on our Site. We will also use information you have provided to us to deliver ongoing information directly or indirectly relevant to the product and/or service you use. We will also use your information to inform you of opportunities, through newsletter, emails, short message service, mail or other electronic forms of communication deemed appropriate, which we believe would be of interest to you based on your activity or membership of our website.   Other ways in which we may use your personal information follow – 

  * to conduct marketing activities and to conduct market research;
  * to customise your online experience and to provide you with more relevant online offers and updates;
  * for regulatory or compliance purposes;
  * to service our relationship with you;
  * to provide you information about any fraudulent activity related to our website; and
  * for internal accounting and administration.

We also track any contact via email when an advertiser has included an email address within a job ad. We track this for the purposes of substantiating a valid contact or application which may bypass the jobsjobsjobs.com.au application process. We retain this contact information indefinitely and use it for the purpose of ensuring your contact is valid and meets that outlined in our terms and conditions located on our website. 

### **Newsletters and email offers**

We will on occasion send you marketing material either directly or indirectly related to your site activity and use of our website. We may use your email address to send you the following types of email messages – 

  * occasional updates about our products and services;
  * occasional marketing offers; and
  * regular scheduled email newsletters related to our products and services;

If you do not wish to receive any of these communications, you can choose to cease any communication, other than fraudulent notice warnings or communication related to administration of your membership or activity on our website, by following the opt out (unsubscribe) process contained within each piece of communication. 

However, if the law requires that we provide you with information about our products or services, we will provide you with that information even if you have chosen not to receive marketing material from us. 

### **Opt Out (Unsubscribe)**

To opt out (unsubscribe) of receiving email offers or newsletters from jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd, follow the opt out (unsubscribe) process (link) contained within each communication piece. Alternatively, you may contact our Privacy officer and request that you be removed from the mailing list for email offers or newsletters. All email offers and email newsletters sent to you by jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd also provide instructions on how to opt out (unsubscribe) of receiving future offers or newsletters. These instructions are usually located at the bottom of the email message. 

### **Access & Correction Of Information About You**

We will, upon a written request by you, provide you with access to the information we hold about you, unless there is an exception which applies under the National Privacy Principles which prevents us from providing you with that personal information.  You are entitled to correct or update the information we hold about you.  We may recover from you our reasonable costs of supplying you with access to the information that we hold about you.  If you request that we provide you with access to your information that we hold about you, we will endeavour to provide that information to you within a reasonable time.  If we refuse to provide you with access to the information, we will provide you with reasons for the refusal and inform you of any exceptions relied upon under the National Privacy Principles. 

### **Keeping Your Personal Information Up–to–Date**

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete and up–to–date.  If you are or become aware that the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete or out–of–date, please contact us and we will take all reasonable steps to correct this information.  Also, if your personal details change, please correct your information online by logging in to your account and selecting “my profile” and by ensuring that your curriculum vitae is up to date. 

### **Disclosure of your personal information to third parties**

We may disclose your personal information to third parties in the following circumstances – 

  * if required to do so or permitted by law;
  * to various regulatory bodies and law enforcement officials and agencies to protect against fraud and for security purposes;
  * to our third party service providers as well as to our related entities, for the purposes of providing the services and/or products you request or purchase from us;

Where we engage third party contractors to perform services for us, those third party contractors may be given access to your personal information for the purposes of providing services to us.  Under these circumstances however, those third party contractors must safeguard this information and must only use it for the purposes for which it was supplied.  If we give a third party service provider your personal information, we will also make them aware of this Privacy Charter and ask that they handle your personal information in accordance with it.  However, beyond this, we will not be liable if they do not comply with this Privacy Charter. 

Other than as described in this section, we will not disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent unless disclosure is – 

(a) necessary to prevent a threat to life or health;

(b) reasonably necessary to enforce any matter; or

(c) necessary to investigate a suspected unlawful activity

### **Trans–Border Data Flows**

For the purposes of providing our services to you, it may be necessary for us to forward personal information to relevant overseas service providers. When you provide us your personal information you give us the consent to do so. If you do not wish jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd to provide this information you will need to email The Privacy Officer and specifically state any objections to such transfers of information. However, we note that we may be not be able to provide you with the products and/or services requested if you object to such trans–border data flows. 

### **Links to other websites**

Our Site contains links to other websites.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those other websites. You are responsible for reading the privacy statements and policies of any linked sites as their privacy policies may differ from ours. 

### **Security**

We have adopted appropriate security features in order to protect and keep secure personal information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction.  We regularly review our security and encryption technologies and strive to protect personal information to the highest level possible. 

### **SSL Technology**

We employ Secure Service Layer (SSL) Technology whenever any transaction is completed over our Site. Transactions involving the passage of personal information occur in one of our secure online areas only.  SSL technology encrypts the information you send through our Site.  The use of SSL technology requires two components – 

  * An SSL–compatible browser; and
  * A web server to perform “key–exchange” that establishes a secure connection.

For you to benefit from the SSL Technology which we have implemented: 

  * you will need a browser with SSL capabilities.  The latest versions of commonly used web browsers generally have this capability.  However, it is your responsibility to check that this is the case.  If you do not already have a browser with SSL capabilities, you can download an SSL browser from a vendor's website.
  * You will also need an internet service provider that enables SSL technology. Nearly all internet service providers automatically enable SSL technology, but you will need to ensure that this is the case with your service provider.

jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd makes no warranty or representation in respect of the strength or effectiveness of the encryption capabilities of SSL Technology and jobsjobsjobs Pty Ltd is not responsible in any way for events arising from any unauthorised access of the information you provide. 

### **Tracking activity on our websites**

When you browse the Site and have not registered for any online products or services, you browse anonymously.  Personally identifiable information – such as your name, address, telephone number and email address – is not collected as you browse.  However, we track how our Site is used by both anonymous visitors and our registered customers, by using a small string of text that is sent to your browser known as a ‘cookie’. Our use of cookies is described in more detail in the next section. 

### **Cookies**

Cookies collect information that include the server your computer is logged onto, your browser type and how you gained entry to the Site.  Therefore, when you visit the Site anonymously, details are recorded about your visit, such as how you have used the Site, the time and date of your access to the Site, pages of the Site that you accessed and the time you spent on the Site.   This information is used in an anonymous form for statistical purposes and as such, cannot be used to identify you individually. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on computer viruses or capture your email address or any other personally identifiable information.  You should note that accepting cookies is required if you want to view our Site, because they are essential for our Site administration and security. 

Our Privacy Officer will respond to you as soon as reasonably practicable.

### **Changes To Our Privacy Charter**

We reserve the right to review and change this Privacy Charter from time to time. Please periodically review this Privacy Charter to stay informed about how we are helping protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of this Site and our services constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Charter and any updates to it. 

### **Further Information on Privacy**

You may obtain further information regarding privacy issues in Australia by visiting the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner’s Site at [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).  Specific enquiries regarding our Privacy Charter should be directed to our Privacy Officer in the manner described above.
